Mitesh Sevani (MSc)

Web Developer

Market London 07877 569 127 msevani@gmail.com www.miteshsevani.com www.github.com/miteshsevani

Profile

Six years experience in web development. A Masters degree with First class honours in E-Commerce with Online Databases. My experience and degree have given me a firm grounding in the core Internet technologies. I have the ability to work as an individual and as part of team. I am highly motivated, well organised and always looking to expand my skills.

Experience

ESI Media (The Independent and Evening Standard) - Mid Level Front End Web Developer February 2016 to Present

- Working as a mid level front end developer
- Delivering a range of apps and features for our stakeholders and clients
- Working with HTML 5, CSS 3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Drupal and some exposure to ReactJS
- The role includes working closely with the design team to build web apps and features from scratch
- Write up documentation for various parts of the website for future reference
- Mentor and train new members of the team

The Engine Group (WCRS) - Web Developer December 2011 to February 2016

- Working for a large digital marketing agency for a global client
- Developing with various front end technologies such as HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, LESS, SASS and Bootstrap
- Progressed to Mid Level Developer where my duties included mentoring and training new and junior developers

Demo Media - Junior Web Developer May 2010 to July 2011

- Working at a small business web agency allowed me to make practical use of the Internet technologies and skills gained during my Masters such as PHP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL database and Internet security
- Clients varied from global banks (Deutsche Bank) to small enterprises giving me the opportunity to develop a range of websites with their own unique requirements
- Involved in all stages of the lifecycle from requirements gathering to testing which allowed me to liaise directly with clients

Accenture Technology Solutions - Internship / Associate Software Engineer July 2005 to July 2006 / October 2007 to July 2008

- Completed a year internship at Accenture, which involved two different projects and various teams (Data migrations, development and testing)
- · Writing and executing test scripts
- Working on a content management system, which involved scripting in TCL and Oracle databases

Education

University of Westminster, London - MSc (Hons) E-Commerce with Online Databases (First) September 2008 to September 2009

Core Modules

- Internet Information Management (X/HTML, XML, XSLT, CSS)
- Database Systems (Oracle 10g)
- Web Application Development (PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Oracle)
- Commercial Web Design (Flash, Action Script, Web Design Concepts)

Dissertation (Content Management System)

My MSc project involved developing a content management system for a voluntary organisation. The CMS allowed the non-technical staff to add, edit and delete content on the homepage of their website. Additional features included statistical analysis of the total attendance at their various branches across the UK and a discussion forum. The project has allowed me to further my knowledge and skills in web application development and design.

City University, London - BSc (Hons) Business Computing Systems (2:2) September 2003 to May 2007

Technical Skills

Development HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, ReactJS (Basic level)

SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, PHP/MySQL, Drupal

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, SQL

Others: Git, Subversion (SVN), Bash Script

Languages Gujarati and Hindi

Extra Curricular

Member of Hindu Swayamsevak Sangh (HSS UK) since the age of 7, which is one of the largest voluntary organisations in the world. Activities include exercise, games and education sessions. Taking regular sessions with all age groups provides me with leadership, communication and organisational skills. Regular attendance has given me team working skills as well as professional development. Involvement in planning, organising and participating in various charity events and camps, both at local and national level.

Travel is one of my main hobbies and interests. I enjoy experiencing various cultures and people and always take the opportunity to travel.

Yoga is also one of my passions and I practice this regularly. I am a qualified Yoga teacher from S-VYASA University in Bangalore, India. I completed the one month Yoga Instructor Course in March 2014.

References Available upon request